Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Moving Images Collection, ca. 1928-2001 UA.Film.Video
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Sports, I.
  - Multiple Sports, 11.
    - Video, 9 items
      - University of Pittsburgh Pitt Promos, November 6, 1991; VHS T-15 1. Pitt/Penn State Football :15 2. Pitt Arena Basketball :30 3. Pitt Arena Basketball :15 (Box 9, Video 283)
      - Hail to Pitt - 1991-1992 Sports Highlights (wih Ron Redmon), unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 21, Video 376)
      - Pitt Baseball 1992 / Pitt Football Highlights 91, unknown; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 29, Video 587)
      - Pitt/Syracuse :30 / Wrestling :30, unknown; Betacam SP 5 Minute (Box 39, Video 801)
      - Baseball / Track, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 39, Video 818)
      - Baseball #23 / #25 John Shultz RHP / Softball, April 1, 1999 AND April 5, 1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 44, Video 981)
      - Michael Novak "In Sport We Trust", February 17, 1977; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 1 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1162)
      - Michael Novak "In Sport We Trust", February 17, 1977; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 2 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1163)
    - DVD, 2 items
      - Thank You for Keeping Your Eye on the Panthers, 2007 (Box 1, Item 11-12)
        Arlotta interview lacks audio.
  - Unknown Sport(s), 12.
    This subseries contains 51 film and videos that either pertain to athletics as a whole or contain footage from unknown sport(s). This series notably includes footage from numerous Pitt athletics' senior banquets and a Big East Conference public service announcement video.
    - Film, 4 items
      - 1971 Pitt vs., 16mm film Media Room 6/6/2 (Box 1, Reel 163)
      - 1971 Pitt vs., 16mm film Media Room 6/6/2 (Box 1, Reel 238)
      - 1972 Pitt vs., 16mm film Media Room 5/6/2 (Box 1, Reel 325)
      - Pitt Physical Fitness, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 1, Reel 978)
    - Video, 47 items
      - Pitt vs. Wisconsin, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA60 (Box 1, Video 458)
      - Pitt vs. Wisconsin - 2, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Tape 2 of ? Needs Case (Box 39, Video 804)
      - The Pittsburgh Panthers 2001 Fan Preview Center Video, unknown; VHS T-15 (Box 4, Video 155)
      - Gene Blahut Audition Tape, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic (Box 7, Video 120)
      - Inside Spring 96, 1996; Betacam SP 60 Minute (Box 7, Video 125)
      - Pitt Panthers - "Dare To Dream", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Needs Case (Box 7, Video 408)
      - "Celebration of Excellence" / "Golden Moment Edit Bed", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBU-5 (Box 8, Video 342)
      - "Celebration of Excellence" - A Golden Moment Edit Bed, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBU-5 (Box 43, Video 962)
      - "Celebration of Excellence" (Final Composite), April 17, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 50, Video 1132)
      - Pitt Spring 1993, unknown; Betacam SP (Box 9, Video 271)
      - 1994 Big East Luncheon Video, Betacam SP 10 Minute (Box 9, Video 275)
      - Seniors 1993 - Dub Master, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 9, Video 293)
      - Roundtable, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 9, Video 146)
      - Press Conference Video, unknown; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 156)
      - Press Conference Video, unknown; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 163)
      - Big East Conference - "Sportsmanship" - August 2001, VHS T-30 (Box 9, Video 161)
      - January 21, 1998 Press Conference Video, VHS T-30 2:15 Video +20:00 Video pad for conference Music Fades (Box 9, Video 168)
      - January 21, 1998 Press Conference Video, VHS T-30 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 176)
      - "Got a Winner Again", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 25, Video 488)
      - Hi-Light Videos 1997, unknown; Betacam SP 90 Minute Needs Case (Box 26, Video 510)
      - Milk is Unnatural - Field Tape 1, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Tape 1 of ? (Box 29, Video 546)
      - Milk is Unnatural - Field Tape Two, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Tape 2 of ? (Box 29, Video 545)
      - Reaction Shots - Milk is Unnatural, Pitt Panthers, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic (Box 29, Video 548)
      - 1992 Senior Award Banquet, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 3 of ? (Box 9, Video 140)
      - Footage 1996 Banquet, Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 29, Video 549)
      - Sports Banquet Seniors 1995, unknown; VHS T30PR (Box 4, Video 152)
      - Senior Banquet 1996, Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 29, Video 560)
      - Pitt / GT #1, unknown; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 29, Video 563)
      - 1989 NCAA Honors Luncheon, VHS (Box 29, Video 575)
      - Heads of Champions?, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 29, Video 584)
      - Dub of: "A Sporting Chance" T: 1 hour, unknown; VHS T-60 (Box 32, Video 630)
      - "Pitt vs Ohio University", unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 32, Video 670)
      - Pitt vs Tulane - Mike Kleinstub <RAW>, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 39, Video 819)
      - Pitt - NDU - 1992 (Pitt Lockerroom), Betacam SP 5 Minute Needs Case (Box 39, Video 820)
      - Pitt 2-25, February 25, ????; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 39, Video 827)
      - Fred Vonappen Interview / Bill Meyers Interview, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 43, Video 939)
      - 1995 PSA, unknown; Betacam SP 10 Minute (Box 43, Video 941)
      - #3 Interviews, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 43, Video 944)
      - Pitt "It's a Winner", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 43, Video 951)
      - Pitt Player Interviews #1, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 43, Video 963)
      - "Pitt Highlights" - Pickup for: Larry Eldridge/Pitt, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR (Box 44, Video 967)
      - S. Off #2, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 2 of ? (Box 45, Video 1042)
      - Pitt Ticket 1992, unknown; Betacam SP 5 Minute (Box 47, Video 1080)
      - Live Lamar A.D. update, August 19, 1993; VHS (Box 47, Video 1081)
      - 93 Rea??? Video Working, unknown; VHS T-30 Needs Case Unknown Title (Box 21, Video 393)
      - Generic Recruiting Vignettes, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 42, Video 917)
      - Take Command of the Game - Basic Training, unknown; VHS (Box 39, Video 787)
- Historical, II.
  - Film, 58 items
    This section contains 58 films which reflect major historical events involving Pitt in the middle of the twentieth century. It notably includes footage of Nikita Khruschev at Pitt, as well as two interviews with Dr. Jonas Salk. This section contains footage from as early as 1928.
    - #1 A Tale of Progress/ History of UPitt, [DVD Available], unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1053)
    - #3 Education is Everybody's Business, 1960; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1019)
    - #3 Education is Everybody's Business/Animated, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1021)
    - #4 The Pennsylvania Way, Pt. 1, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 974)
    - #5 The Pennsylvania Way, Pt. 2, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 977)
    - #6 The Pennsylvania Way, Pt. 3, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 976)
    - #7 The Pennsylvania Way, Pt. 4, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 975)
    - #8 Interview with Dr. Hoffman, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1024)
    - #10 Edward R. Murrow Interviews Jonas Salk on "See it Now", [DVD Available], unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 998)
    - #11 "Meet the Professor" Jonas Salk, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 999)
    - #12 Chancellor Litchfield 1962, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1026)
    - #13 Meet the Professor Edwin Peterson, May 21, 1962; 1 film 1000' 16mm 6/6/4 (Box 39, Reel 1,079)
    - #15 Hootenanny/TV Folk Music Program, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1018)
    - #18 Annual Report 1963-1964, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1062)
    - #19 General Activities Pt. 2/Alumni Trip to Europe, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1020)
    - #20 General Activities Pt. 3/Commencement Ceremonies, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 988)
    - #21 General Activities Pt. 4/Campus Models, Proposed Projects, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 989)
    - #22 General Activities Pt. 5/Other Pitt Campuses, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 990)
    - #23 General Activities Pt. 6/Buildings, Construction, Dedication of Buildings, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 991)
    - #24 General Activities Pt. 7/Students and Projects, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 987)
    - #25 General Activities Pt. 8/Activities and Departments, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 986)
    - #26 General Activities Pt. 9/Nationality Rooms, Conferences, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 985)
    - #27 General Activities Pt. 10/ Arts Labs General Activities, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 984)
    - #28 General Activities Pt. 11/ Dedications, Special Events, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 983)
    - #29 General Activities Pt. 12/ Plaques, Pictures, Plans, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 982)
    - #30 General Activities Pt. 13/Libraries, Labs, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 995)
    - #31 General Activities Pt. 14/Professors in Action, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 996)
    - #32 General Activities Pt. 15/Buildings on Campus, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 997)
    - #33 General Activities Pt. 16/Students, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 993)
    - #34 General Activities Pt. 17/Miscelleanous Students, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 992)
    - #36-42 Khruschev at Pitt [Khrushchev], 1959; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 #36 = Reel 36 (Part 5 of 5) #37 = Reel 1002 (Part 3 of 5) #38 = Reel 1001 (Part 2 of 5) #39 = Reel 1000 (silent) #40 = Reel 1006 (silent) #41 = Reel 1078 (Part 4 of 5) #42 = Reel 1003 (Part 1 of 5) (Box 39, Reel 36)
    - #43 1928 Graduation at Dental School, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1027)
    - #44 Seniors Receive Grades at Dental Library 1929, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1028)
    - #45 1929 Psi Omega Picnic, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1081)
    - #46 1930 Psi Omega Picnic, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1029)
    - #47 1932 Psi Omega Picnic, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1030)
    - #48 1940 Psi Omega Picnic, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1045)
    - #49 Psi Omega Picnic, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1031)
    - #51 Litchfield and Supreme Court Justice Tom Clark/Scenes of Pitt vs. Navy Game 1964, Unknown and 1964; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1033)
    - #54 Dedication of Engineering Hall, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1038)
    - #55 Man Paints Cathedral of Learning Portraits, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1037)
    - #56 Footage of Classroom Lectures and Discussions, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1039)
    - #57 1958 U.S. Educators Visit Moscow, 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1040)
    - #58 Higher Education in USSR, Litchfield, Other University Presidents in USSR, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1022)
    - #59 Soviet Education NBC News, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1023)
    - #60 Pitt Evening Classes, unknown; 16mm film Contains 4 Reels Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1055)
    - #61 Pitt Evening Classes, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1059)
    - #66 Upward: A History of Pitt, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1080)
    - #74 Upward: A Story of the High Place/ A History of Pitt, [DVD Available], unknown; Three 16mm film reels (#1050, 1051, 1054) Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1050)
    - #79 Litchfield Etal Valparaiso, Chile, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1048)
    - Salute to Carl Olson, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1008)
    - Salute to Carl Olson, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 39, Reel 1009)
    - V.F.E.W.D. Local 105 Peoria, Caterpillar Tractor Co.-Oct. 41, October ??, 1941; 16mm film Media Room 4/8/4 (Box 39, Reel 1066)
    - Kruschev & David Lawrence at Pitt, 1959
    - Senior Queen, 1940
    - Interview with Colodny about Cuba, ca. 1960
    - Presentation to Eisenhower, 1973
  - Video
    This section contains videos which pertain to the history of either the University of Pittsburgh or the city of Pittsburgh. It notably includes footage of the unveiling of Pitt's Varsity Walk, as well as some for commencement programs.
    - Ground Breaking Ceremony, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 4, Video 151)
    - Ground Breaking Ceremony, unknown; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 172)
    - Ground Breaking #1, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic 20BQ Needs Case (Box 4, Video 153)
    - Ground Breaking #2, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic 20BQ Needs Case (Box 9, Video 154)
    - Aerial footage April '91 Dusk, April ??, 1991; Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 8, Video 128)
    - The Editors - Friday July 5th - nordenberg interview, unknown; VHS T-40 (Box 8, Video 339)
    - Varsity Walk Unveiling, April 6, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 9, Video 139)
    - 1994 Pitt Commencement w/Doug Whaley & Matt Bloom, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 9, Video 142)
    - Pitt Project, unknown; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 28, Video 535)
    - Pitt Project Carnegie - 1937, unknown; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 28, Video 536)
    - Bob Wiley Presentation #1, unknown; VHS Needs Case (Box 9, Video 173)
    - Vets Hyland Tape 1, unknown; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 29, Video 540)
    - History, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 39, Video 817)
    - 100 Yrs. Pitt - Music 2 Cuts Ch1 only, unknown; Betacam SP 10 Minute (Box 21, Video 372)
    - Pitt Auditions, unknown; VHS T-10 (Box 43, Video 961)
    - Pitt Senior Ceremonies, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 43, Video 958)
    - Pitt Show Air Lock (Reel Footage), August 30, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 52, Video 1147)
    - Pitt Pride 1987 Reel Footage (Reel A), unknown; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 52, Video 1146)
    - "Miner Picket West Penn Power--Masontown, PA", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBU-18 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 52, Video 1156)
    - Roberts Jaworski and Peter Flaherty: Native Son I, September 6, 1991; VHS T-15 :30 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 52, Video 1158)
    - Gold Medal Presentation/Dr. Posvar Presentation, October 27, 1990; Betacam SP Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 52, Video 1159)
    - TCI 1996, unknown; VHS (Box 43, Video 956)
    - Chancellor W.W. Posvar comments on proposed state budget that would eliminate aid to the University (broadcast on 6 p.m. news, WIIC, WTAE, KDKA-TV), August 4, 1977; 3/4 Inch U-matic Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1174)
    - Flood victims housed at the University of Pittsburgh's Johnstown campus, July 28, 1977; 3/4 Inch U-matic Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1171)
    - Debate on J.P. Stevens Co. vs Union, July 13, 1977; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 1 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1176)
    - Debate on J.P. Stevens Co. vs Union, July 13, 1977; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 2 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1177)
    - "An Uncommon Woman" (Judge Genevieve Blatt) March 3, 1988 produced by Governor's Cultural Advisor, Length 28:08, VHS T-30 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 3, Video 1179)
    - The University of Pittsburgh Archives with Marilyn Whitmore and Jeannine Kreyenbuhl, 1982?; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-30 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 3, Video 1180)
    - General Matthew B. Ridgway Dinner on the occasion of naming the Center for International Security Studies in his honor 4/21/88, April 21, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-60 Tape 1 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 3, Video 1181)
    - General Matthew B. Ridgway Dinner on the occasion of naming the Center for International Security Studies in his honor 4/21/88, April 21, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-60 Tape 2 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 3, Video 1182)
    - Greek Sing 1984, March 1984; 3/4 Inch U-matic Copy 1 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1183)
    - Greek Sing 1984, March 1984; 3/4 Inch U-matic Copy 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1184)
    - Greek Sing 1985, March 1985; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1185)
    - Greek Sing 1986, March 1986; VHS T-120 Tape 1 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1195)
    - Greek Sing 1986, March 1986; VHS T-120 Tape 2 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1196)
    - Greek Sing 1987, March 1987; VHS Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1197)
    - Greek Week 1988-"Lighting the Way", March 1988; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1191)
    - Greek Week 1988-Commercials, news clips, March 1988; VHS T-120 Tape 1 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1192)
    - Greek Sing 1988, March 1988; VHS T-120 Tape 2 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1193)
    - Greek Sing 1988, March 1988; VHS T-120 Tape 3 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1194)
    - Greek Week Dance Marathon – April 9, 1989, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1190)
    - Greek Week Dance Marathon – March 31, 1990, March 30-31, 1990; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1189)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement Press Conference April 1990, April 30, 1990; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1188)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement April 1990, April 30, 1990; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 53, Video 1187)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement -Paul O'Neill, April 27, 2003; VHS 1:41:10 (Box 48, Video 1,257-1,258)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement -Paul C. Lauterbur, April 25, 2004; VHS 2:43 (Box 48, Video 1,259-1,261)
    - Graduation Video (Hi Mom), April 23, 2004; VHS Skutski and Oldmanns 19:23 Looped 38:52 (Box 48, Video 1,262)
    - Founder's Day Ball February 1987, 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1200)
    - Dr. John M. Roberts (Anthropology Dept.) interviewed by Dr. Jeremy Sabloff (Anthropology Dept.) on December 5, 1988 for the Oral History of Anthropology Project sponsored by the University of Florida Anthropology Dept., VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1203)
    - The Editors: Interview with Wesley Posvar. September 13, 1989, VHS T-30 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1204)
    - Dr. Jacob G. Birnberg, Provost Inaugural Lecture, April 21, 1994 "An Overview of Management Control Systems", VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1206)
    - Hart and Corrier – 11/9/78, November 9, 1978; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA 60 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1208)
    - "Fishbait" Miller, November 15, 1977; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA 60 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 Student Union Ballroom - 12 noon (Box 54, Video 1210)
    - Gongshow - Summer 1977, 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 1 of ? Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1211)
    - Women in Mathematical Sciences Connected to Industry, February 23-25, 1996, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1213)
    - INFORMATION IN SOCIETY 7/18/98: Mulhollan, Daniel P. Directory, Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress "Confidentiality and Objectivity in the Legislative Environment", July 18, 1994; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1214)
    - Martin Walker/Ethics Forum – October 7, 1996 "Give us Back Our Good Names: Media, Ethics, and Character.", VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1215)
    - Dean's Forum on the Ethics of Information in Society: Betti Clipsham – October 26, 1994. "Building the Ethical Corporation: The Motorola Story.", VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1216)
    - International Student Party - January 17, 1992, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1217)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement 1990, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 Needs Case (Box 54, Video 1221)
    - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Research Update. V. 1 Summer 1991, VHS T-20 Tape 1 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1222)
    - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Research Update. V. 2 Winter 1992, VHS T-20 Tape 2 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1223)
    - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Research Update. V. 3 Summer 1992, VHS T-20 Tape 3 of 3 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1224)
    - Perspectives on the Dick Thornburgh Archival Collection. Founder's Day February 27, 1998, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 10, Video 1226)
    - University of Pittsburgh "Homecoming" 1992 (version 1), VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 10, Video 1227)
    - "The Information Age Unbridled" lecture – Robert E. Allen (AT&T Corporation) Information Science Lecture 11/11/97, November 11, 1991; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 10, Video 1228)
    - University of Pittsburgh PITT IN REVIEW, unknown; VHS T-30 RT 11:30 (Box 48, Video 1254)
    - Pitt Cap and Gown Club – Gene Kelly, 1933-1936
  - DVD, 10 items
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement, May 1, 2005 (Box 1, Item 1-3)
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement, 2008 (Box 1, Item 4-6)
      Speaker is Dan Marino.
    - University of Pittsburgh Commencement, 2010 (Box 1, Item 7-9)
    - Chancellor's Message to Alumni, 2006 (Box 1, Item 10)
- Promotional, III.
  This series contains promotional films and videos which pertain to the University of Pittsburgh. This notably includes institutional messages as well as promotions for academic programs, alumni and sports.
  - Video, 57 items
    - University of Pittsburgh Institutional Message 1990 (Commons), February 19, 1990; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS10BR (Box 8, Video 131)
    - "University of Pittsburgh Institutional Message", August 26, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 10 :30 (Box 7, Video 123)
    - Institutional Message - 1988, 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 5 (Box 43, Video 947)
    - Institutional Message - 1989, September 13, 1989; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR 10 (Box 46, Video 1054)
    - University of Pittsburgh "Institutional Message 1996-1997" TRT :30, unknown; Betacam SP TRT :30 (Box 9, Video 287)
    - University of Pittsburgh "Institutional Message- New Logo w/ Disk", August 16, 2001; Betacam SP :30 (Box 9, Video 167)
    - University of Pittsburgh "The Place to Be" Institutional Spot, unknown; VHS T15 :30 (Box 4, Video 174)
    - University of Pittsburgh "The Place to Be" Institutional Spot, unknown; VHS 30 Second (Box 9, Video 169)
    - University of Pittsburgh "The Place To Be" Cinelook Copy, unknown; VHS T15 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 149)
    - University of Pittsburgh "The Place To Be" 30 Second Institutional, unknown; VHS T-15 Needs Case (Box 42, Video 940)
    - WTAE Promo, August 16, 1977; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 7, Video 352)
    - "Follow Us Back To Pitt", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 10 8:55 w/ bars and credits (Box 7, Video 121)
    - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center - A Celebration of Excellence, April 25, 1986; VHS T60BA 30 Minute (Box 8, Video 137)
    - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center - A Celebration of Excellence, April 25, 1986; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 9, Video 171)
    - "Couch Potatoe[sic] Commercial", unknown; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 9, Video 141)
    - Pitt Promo TRT :30, September 21, 1995; Betacam SP :30 (Box 9, Video 295)
    - "The Pitt Experience" Back Up Master, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 9, Video 145)
    - The Pittsburgh Experience - Master Music, unknown; Betacam SP 60 Minute (Box 21, Video 398)